# INYOUNG CHEONG

+1(206) 945-5031 Bellevue, WA

icheon@uw.edu inyoungcheong.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am dedicated to researching the private and public regulation of **free speech** and **privacy** in the context of **social media** and most recently, **generative AI and large language models**. My research employs a combination of legal analysis, informed by my formal law and policy training, and qualitative methods from computer science to delve into the complexities of internet regulation.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Ph.D. Candidate, University of Washington School of Law

Expected 2024

Advisor: <u>Tadayoshi Kohno</u>, Affiliations: <u>Security & Privacy Lab</u> at UW School of Computer Science & Engineering (Member, 2022-) | <u>UW Tech Policy Lab</u> (Member, 2022-) | Science, Technology & Society Studies (Member, 2021-) | Global Business Law Institute (Fellow, 2021-2022) | Washington Journal of Law, Technology & Arts (Submission Editor, 2021-2023) | UW Asia-Pacific Law Student Association (VP, 2020-2021)

Dissertation topic: Free Speech, Content Moderation, and Algorithmic Decision-making

## Master of Law (LL.M.), Seoul National University School of Law

Feb. 2018

Major: Administrative Law Achievements: Academic Excellence Award Dissertation: "Alternative Dispute Resolution and the Right to Fair Trial"

## Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Hongik University

Feb. 2012

Major: Economics, Art Philosophy Achievements: Academic Excellence Award (12/13 Semesters) Dissertation: "Justice Sentiment and Aesthetic Judgment: Immanuel Kant's and David Hume's Moral Theories"

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Affiliate Instructor, UW School of Law

Jan. 2023 - Mar. 2023 Seattle, WA

• Taught "Technology Law and Public Policy Seminar" to 25 J.D. and LL.M. students with a specific focus on algorithms as speech, different notions of privacy, and content moderation.

Research Assistant, UW School of Computer Science & Engineering

Sep. 2022 - present Seattle, WA

• Advised by Tadayoshi Kohno, have explored collaborative governance models that leverage the expertise and incentives of various stakeholders to promote trust and safety through legal and qualitative methods.

Deputy Director, Ministry of Culture, Sports, and Tourism

May 2016 - Aug. 2019 Sejong, South Korea

- Formulated a strategic plan, "Future Technology for Culture & Arts," by gathering the opinions of businesses, researchers, academics, and civil society, leading to a record-setting budget increase (\$100 million a year).
- Executed art funds for Webtoon and Fashion design. Supported Webtoon (digital comics) artists to formulate the industry's self-regulatory body in a collaboration with major Webtoon platforms.

Deputy Director, Korea Communications Commission

Oct. 2012 - May 2016 Gwachun, South Korea

- Interpreted relevant laws, implemented user experiments and coordinated conflicting political views to ensure the successful grant of a license to operate to a public broadcasting channel.
- Reviewed bills related to media convergence and digital platforms and drafted over 200 Commission statements about their impacts on users' fundamental rights including free speech and privacy.
- Led an investigation into a deceptive advertising scandal involving the leading national newspaper. Upon uncovering evidence of violations, took decisive action by imposing injunctions and fines on the newspaper.

Summer Associate (Intern), Administrative Conference of the United States Summer 2021 Washington DC

• Performed comprehensive research on complex case law and statutes, and global regulations on the removal of agency heads and legal implications of automated decisions within the U.S. federal government.

• Formulated and cultivated sustainable development goals-conscious strategic regional partnerships, called "UN75 Cities," with South Korean local governments, while directly reporting to the Under-Secretary-General.

Administrator Apprentice, National Institute of Policy Training April 2012 - Oct. 2012 Gwachun, South Korea

- Achieved the honor of being one of 100 candidates selected from a pool of 5,500 to pass the national exam.
- Undertook a rigorous 6-month law and foreign affairs training and graduated 2nd place out of 100 candidates.

# Intern Curator, Pyo Gallery Seoul

Dec. 2008 - Feb. 2009 Seoul, South Korea

• Assisted in curating Jonathan Borofsky's exhibition, "Human Structures and the Light of Consciousness."

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Inyoung Cheong, Aylin Caliskan, and Tadayoshi Kohno, "<u>Law, Language Models, and Security</u>: An Examination of Unintentional and Adversarial Harms of Large Language Models (2023)
- Inyoung Cheong, "Freedom of Algorithmic Expression", The University of Cincinnati Law Review Vol. 91 (2023)
- Inyoung Cheong, Pardis Emami-Naeini, and Tadayoshi Kohno, "Multistakeholder Content Moderation: A Collaborative Approach to Online Speech Governance", The Journal of Online Trust and Safety 2023 (pending)
- Inyoung Cheong, "The U.S. Federal Administrative Law and Civil Penalties", Administrative Law Journal (Korean) Vol. 69 (2022)
- Inyoung Cheong, "Legislative, Executive, and Judicial Reactions to Facebook Data Breach I: The California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018," The Journal of Law and Economic Regulation (Korean) Vol. 12. No. 2. (2020)
- Inyoung Cheong, "Legislative, Executive, and Judicial Reactions to Facebook Data Breach II: The U.S. Federal Courts' Consumer Class Actions", The Journal of Law and Economic Regulation (Korean) Vol. 13. No. 1. (2020)
- Inyoung Cheong, "Legislative, Executive, and Judicial Reactions to Facebook Data Breach III: The Federal Trade Commission's 5-Billion Dollar Settlements", *The Journal of Law and Economic Regulation (Korean)* Vol. 13. No. 2. (2021)
- Inyoung Cheong, "Korea Communications Commission's Adjudication on Deceptive News Reports", The Journal of Law and Economic Regulation (Korean) Vol. 9. No. 1. (2016)
- Inyoung Cheong, "Korea's New Trends in Culture and Art Legislation: Artists' Welfare and Fair Competition", The Journal of Law and Economic Regulation (Korean) Vol. 10. No. 1. (2017)
- Inyoung Cheong, "Amendments to the Broadcasting Act in 2013-2014", The Journal of Law and Economic Regulation (Korean) Vol. 7. No. 1. (2014)
- Inyoung Cheong, "Private and Public Space," in *Divertas Vol.* 14, Korea University Divertas Press (2021)

#### RESEARCH PROJECTS

- "Comparative Analysis of Civil Penalties," Korea Legislation Research Institute (2022) | Co-Principal Investigator
- "The EU Artificial Intelligence Act," Korea Legislation Research Institute (2021) | Legal Translator
- "Historical Analysis of South Korea's Regulatory Innovation," Korea Legislation Research Institute & Korea Public Law Association (2020) | Co-Principal Investigator
- "Reforming the Cloud Computing Act," Ministry of Science, Technology, and ICT (2020) | Investigator
- "Innovations in Global Smart Farms," Rural Development Administration of Korea (2020) | Investigator

## AWARDS, HONORS, AND SCHOLARSHIPS

- Fulbright Grant for Ph.D. Program (\$70,000) | The U.S. Department of State (2019-2021)
- Best Poster Award | Korean-American Scientists and Engineers Association (Nov. 2022)
- Global Business Law Institute Fellowship | University of Washington School of Law (2020-2021)
- Homecoming Scholarship 2021 | University of Washington Alumni Association (Oct. 2021)
- SHK Group Scholarship (\$3,000) | Korean Bar Association of Washington (May. 2021)
- Distinguished Public Service Award | Korea Comic Studies Association (Jul. 2019)
- Distinguished Public Service Award | Education Broadcasting Service, Inc. (Feb. 2016)

#### CONFERENCES

- Poster, "Social Media's Algorithmic Freedom?" Northwest Research Conference 2022

  \*Best Poster Award

  Nov. 2022 Seattle, United States
- Poster, "Social Media's Algorithmic Freedom?" Trust and Safety Research Conference 2022, Stanford Internet Observatory

  Sep. 2022 San Francisco, United States
- **Presenter**, "Online Content Co-regulation: Case Study of South Korea", TrustCon 2022, Trust and Safety Professionals Association Sep. 2022 Stanford, United States
- **Keynote Speaker**, "Unpacking Government R&D Processes: Do's and Don'ts when applying for R&D Funds", Metaverse and Future of Media Workshop Conference Oct. 2021 Seoul, South Korea
- **Presenter**, "Advanced Digital Technology and Regulatory Innovation", The Korea Public Law Association Conference

  Dec. 2020 Seoul, South Korea
- **Presenter**, "Why I Came Back to School from the Government Position", Annual Fulbright Scholars Western Chapter Conference Feb. 2020 Seattle, United States
- Moderator, "Data Privacy Legislation Trends in South Korea", American Bar Association e-Privacy Committee
   Workshop
   Aug. 2020 Washington DC, US
- **Presenter**, "Is the Administrative Agency's Dispute Resolution Practice Unconstitutional?" The Korea Society of Mediation Annual Conference

  Aug. 2018 Seoul South Korea
- **Presenter**, "Legislative Control over Government Surveillance for National Security Purposes," The Korea Society of Police Law Annual Conference Feb. 2016 Chuncheon, South Korea
- **Presenter**, "Government Strategies to Promote Korean Designers to Global Market," The Korea Association of Styling and Textile Annual Conference

  Aug. 2018 Seoul Seoul, South Korea
- **Presenter**, "Government Strategies to Foster Local Webtoon Industries," The Korea Institute of Cartoon Culture Workshop

  Feb. 2017 Seoul, South Korea

#### **HOBBIES**

- Playing classical piano (trained since age 5, performed in a high school choir and local competitions)
- Experimenting with different mediums in my artwork, including watercolor and digital painting (gallery)
- Frequent attendance at classical art events (Member of the Seattle Art Museum and Seattle Symphony)
- Enthusiastic about fictions (a founder of book clubs in three different workplaces. Favorite authors include Milan Kundera, Luise Rinser, Leo Tolstoy, Hua Yu, Kenzaburō Ōe, Kwon Yeo-sun, Murakami Haruki . . . .)
- Cooking Korean foods (e.g., kimchi fried rice, japchae) but also enjoying baking pizzas and making pasta